Hello.
So here we will be talking about radio frequency, power and signal interface.
Contactless cards do not require any electrical connection between the smart card and the reader, or
the card terminal to transmit power and data over a short distance.
The methods used for transmitting power and data with contactless cards are not new.
They have been generally known for many years in the world of radio frequency identification, like
RFID system, which are used in a wide variety of applications such as animal and plants, and transponders
for electronic multi-start systems in vehicles.
To facilitate understanding these methods, they can be classified according to diverse parameters.
One approach is to classify them according to the method used to transmit power and data.
The most used method are radio waves or microwaves.
Optical transmission capacity, stiff coupling and inductive coupling.
Just as with contact smart cards, the system with contactless cards consists of at least two components
a card and a compatible terminal, so pick and the compatible reader.
The terminal or the reader can act as a reader of or a reader or writer according to the technology
used as a rule, the terminal includes an additional interface for communication with the background
system.
So as you can see in this picture here we will have the terminal and the contactless smart card, which
is which is the pack.
The following four functions are necessary to allow a contactless card to communicate with the terminal.
Power transmission to the card for powering the integrated circuit clock signal transmission data transmission
to the card, and then data transmission from the card, which presents the answer.
So as we said earlier, the inductive coupling is the key of any communication between the reader and
the card.
In fact, all cards that employ inductive coupling work on the same principle, regardless of their
range or power consumption.
One or more coils are incorporated in the card body to act as coupling components for power and data
transmission, along with one or more chips.
A variety of methods are commonly used to produce the coil and connect the coil to the chip.
So about power transmission.
In fact, contactless smart cards are always operated passively.
This means that all the power necessary for the operation of the chip in the card must be transmitted
from the terminal to the card.
This is done using the principle of a loosely coupled transformer, as illustrated in this picture.
The transformer coil belonging to the terminal is used to generate a strong high frequency electromagnetic
field.
The frequency is most used for this purpose are are lower sorry than 135kHz and 1350 six megahertz.
This means that the wavelength of the electromagnetic field is several times larger than the distance
between the card and the terminal.
This allows the loosely coupled transformer model to be used if a contactless card is brought into the
vicinity of the terminal, part of the magnetic field passes through the coil of the card, which causes
an AC voltage to be generated in the coil.
This voltage is rectified and used to power the chip.
So here on the left we have the terminal and the right we have the smart card, which and one of the
components of the smart card is the chip.
The coupling between the terminal coil and the card coil is very weak, so the efficiency of this arrangement
is very low.
Consequently.
Consequently, a very strong current must flow in the terminal coil in order to generate the necessary
field strength.
This is achieved by connecting a capacitor kBT in parallel with the coil light.
As you can see in the picture, with the capacitance chosen such that the resonance frequency of the
circuit formed by the coil and the capacitor matched the frequency of the signal used to transmit power
to the card coil LC and capacitor C1 in the card also form a resonant circuit with the same resonance
frequency.
The voltage and usage in the card is proportional to the signal frequency, the number of turns in coil
RLC, and the area enclosed by the coil.
This means that the number of turns needed for the coil drops.
With increasing the signal frequency.
At 125kHz, it's 100 to 1000 turns, while at 1350 six megahertz it's only 3 to 10.
So all known digital modulation methods can be used for transmitting data from the terminal to the card,
or from the reader to the card, or from PC to PC.
The most commonly used methods are amplitude shift keying, ask frequency shift keying, FSK, and phase
shift keying.
PSK, Ask, and PSK are most often used since they are especially easy to demodulate.
So contactless RF smart cards operating at 1350 six megahertz are powered and communicate with the reader
via inductive coupling of the reader antenna to the card antenna.
Two loop antennas effectively form a transformer.
Alternating.
An alternating magnetic field is produced by sinusoidal current flowing through the reader antenna loop.
When the card enters this alternating magnetic field, an alternating current AC is induced in the current
loop antenna.
The Pic integrated circuit contains a rectifier and power regulator to convert the the AC to direct
to direct current to power the integrated circuit.
So this part is, as we have seen earlier and as I said before, the 1350 six megahertz is the frequency
that characterizes the NFC technology.
So, as I said, when the card enters the alternating magnetic field, an alternating current is induced
in the card loop antenna.
The Pic integrated circuit contains a rectifier and power regulator to convert the AC to direct current
to power the integrated circuit.
As we said, for the communication between from PCD to Pic, we use the modulation of the carrier and
the other way.
From PSC to PCD, we use the load modulation technique.
So the carrier frequency and power transfer are one of the analog characteristics of the communication
between the PCD and the PCC.
The carrier frequency, which characterizes by FC of an RFID system, as defined by the ISO 14 443,
is 1350 six megahertz plus -seven kilohertz.
The carrier is used to supply power to the PCC via transformer coupling and the resulting induced voltage.
The modulation of the carrier signal allows the PCD to transmit information to the PCC.
So from PCD to PAC, we use the modulation of the carrier.
The PCD or a reader shall generate a field of at least h mean and not exceeding h max at manufacturer
specified positions or operating volume.
The PAC shall operate as intended continuously between H, min, and max.
This includes all PAC requirements defined in the standard and processing of the manufacturer specified
set of commands.
The values of H, min, and max are the following for each class.
As you can see here in this table we have a niche mean and h max.
For example, for class one is from 1.5 to 7.5.
For class three it's from 1.5 to 8 point 5 ampere/m, the same as class two.
And then in the end from for class six, it's from 4.5A/m to 18 ampere/m.
As we have seen earlier, when we go higher in the number of the class, we go lower on the size of
the antenna, the dimensions of the antenna.
In fact, a card, for example, in a class one card, an ID one card based on the ISO standard, it
should work from h mean to h max.
So from one 5 ampere/m to 7.5A/m.
But usually the manufacturer fabricate this card to be able to support or to boot by a field value lower
than 1.5 can be 0.8 0.51A/m.
So let's think is the communication speed or let's say the bit rate.
When you have a look in the standard you don't find the word speed.
It's mostly bit rate.
So the bit rate when communication is being initialized is is 106kbps, which corresponds to the quotient
fc divided by 128.
So 1350 six megahertz divided by 128.
After initialization, the following bit rates are available.
Depending on the pick function, it means that the first part of the communication before we start exchanging
information is done at 106 kilobit per second.
Whatever the type of the communication, type A or type B, there is specific, specific response that
gives us information about the bitrates or the speeds supported by the pack or the card.
And there is a specific protocol that the PCD and the pack perform to agree on a specific bitrate.
To continue the communication with.
So here, in fact, in the ISO standard we have seven values of the speed.
Basically the communication between a reader and a car start always at 106 at 106, until we reach the
exchange of information, until we reach the exchange of I blocks.
So first we have 106 kilobit per second, 212 kilobit per second, for 24 kilobit per second and eight
48 kilobit per second.
These are the normal bit rates in the standard.
You will find them in this way.
Then we have the higher speeds which are called very high baud rate, which are 1.7mbps, 3.4mbps and
6.8mbps.